hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TSA automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles with trst tosa
let's look our next obstacle which is
called The Escape now in this particular
obstacle we need to input the value
click into the text box now you will
think that why it is an obstacle we can
directly type this value into the text
box but when you scan this particular
module and you are trying to enter click
into the value then by default it will
think that it is the click operation and
what it will do is it will try to click
on the text box rather than entering it
as a value and that is why it is a
little tricky but not that difficult so
what basically we can do here is uh we
can use something called Escape
characters in tosa so this is basically
used in case we want to escape some
special characters but you can use it
for any particular text so let's see how
we can automate this particular obstacle
in tosa now okay so going back to tosa
the first step is always the same we
need to scan this particular module so
let's go ahead and scan this
now okay and then U I'm going
to scan this particular text box which
is called the result text and I'm going
to save this and close
it let's go back
here and I'm going to just rename
this okay so now coming back to our tosa
obstacle disc cases let's create a new
one here and then uh let's add the
module which we have scanned
earlier okay so we have got uh the
particular text box right here um and
now we need to enter click into that
particular text box now as I was
mentioning if we directly try to use the
click uh as this okay so it will by
default become the click operation
because tosa cannot tell that you are
trying to click on it or you are trying
to enter a particular text okay because
this is a system defined operation and
this is the expression which is used so
tosa will always take it as the default
click
operation now if you want to make it a
simple text right then we need to escape
all the characters in this particular
text and that can be done in two
different ways so uh you can right click
on this particular value and then you
will get an option to escape the value
okay or uh you can directly also uh
enclose the whole text inside double
quotes so this will basically Escape all
your characters which are contained
inside this double quotes Okay and then
tosa will uh consider it as a normal
text and not as a special expression uh
which is related to any particular
operation
okay so now uh this is what we need to
do here uh so we'll mark it as completed
and we'll try to execute it in the
scratchbook okay so as you can see uh it
entered click uh as a particular text
into the text box and the automation
obstacle was marked as completed
so this is how you can escape characters
at different places uh in your test
cases so that TSA consider it as a
normal text rather than any special
characters or any particular
expression that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next video